hey guys so we want to solve the radius
of this circle first let's find the
center of the circle and this right here
is going to be the radius I first
thought it was maybe it equals 1 but it
doesn't cuz if we bring this down that's
not in the middle here cuz the edge of
the circle is not in the middle either
so we can't really do that next let's
look at this diagonal here we can
actually find out what this diagonal is
cuz this is a right angle so if we call
this side a this side B and this side C
we know that a s + B2 is equal to c^2 a
right here is equal to 2 the B is the
same as this right here so it's equal to
2 and then C will just leave as c^ S 2 s
is 4 + 2^ 2 is 4 is equal to c^ 2 4 + 4
is 8 we square root both sides on the
left hand side we can break < TK of8
into < of 4 * < TK of two and the < TK
of 4 is 2 and on the right hand side it
just becomes C so we can clean this
stuff up up here and let's put 2 < tk2
right here for this piece of the
diagonal let's get rid of all this stuff
unfortunately the diameter here is not 2
< tk2 because it doesn't go all the way
to the corner but we can say that the
rest of the diagonal right up here is
also 2k2 so we can calculate the
diagonal of the big square and it's
going going to be equal to the 2 < tk2
plus the 2 < tk2 which is just 4 < tk2
and we can put a box around that let's
clean this all up a little bit and this
right here is the radius we'll call that
R this is what we're trying to solve for
so we know this we know this we just got
to find this piece right here that's not
too bad because we can make a square
right here we know each of these are
equal to the radius as well so we can
call both the sides of this Square R
then we can do another diagonal we'll
move this R over to here and if we make
the diagonal equal to C then we know
that R 2 + R2 = c^2 well R2 + r 2 is 2 r
squ we can square root both sides the
left hand side can be broken out into <
TK of 2 * < TK of R 2 and the right hand
side would just bequ < TK of c squ and
then s of R squ is just R and squ of c^
squ is just C and we can smush these
together and we have > of 2 R is equal
to C up here was our diagonal C so we
can change that into < tk2 R clean
things up a little bit and now what do
we have big diagonal again this time
it's equal to this diagonal here the 2 <
tk2 plus the r plus the < tk2 r and we
can put a box around that but we know
that the big diagonal has to equal the
big diagonal so we're just going to set
the 4 < tk2 for this side of the big
diagonal equal to all of this and now we
only have one variable R and one
equation so once we solve for R we know
the answer we can subtract 2 < tk2 from
both sides the left hand side becomes 2
< tk2 the right hand side that's gone so
it's just this right here and we can
scoot these over and let's Factor an R
out of the right hand side so R * what
gives us R that's one so R * 1 is r and
then R * what gives us < tk2 R well
that's going to be < tk2 so if you
imagine Distributing this it would bring
us back to where we were up here so we
factored out the r then on the left hand
side leave that as 2 < tk2 the 1 plus <
tk2 is just a number so we can divide
both sides by that number and we end up
with r being equal to 2 < tk2 over 1 + <
tk2 and we can plug it into a calculator
and get a decimal approximation of 17157
and that keeps going it's irrational and
now we have the answer to our question
the radius is approximately
17157 and we put a box around that how
exciting